A Guide to the William Houlder Hudgins Papers, 1846-1895
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Papers, 1846-1895
Library of Virginia
24973
.9 cubic feet
William Houlder Hudgins
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William Raymond Thomas, Washington D.C., 16 May 1959.
Biographical Information
William Houlder Hudgins was born 25 April 1826 in Mathews County, Virginia. He served as as Commissioner of Accounts, Commissioner in Chancery, and Justice of the Peace for Mathews County, Virginia. He also owned and operated a general store. Hudgins died 18 December 1895.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1846-1895, of William Houlder Hudgins (1826-1895) of Mathews County, Virginia, consisting of accounts, appraisals, blank forms, daybooks, deeds, estate records, ledgers, letters, lists, minutes, promissory notes, and receipts. Papers cover Hudgins' tenure as Commissioner of Accounts, 1859 and 1868-1895, and Commissioner in Chancery, 1874-1886, for Mathews County and contains accounts for estates and trusts in Mathews County; records from his tenure as justice of the peace from 1870-1895; examination of the Mathews County Treasurer's Bond for 1879, 1883, and 1891-1892; estate papers, 1861-1894, including papers of the Respress estate and John J. Callis estate; fiduciaries, 1871-1892; promissory notes to Hudgins, 1853-1862; and blank legal forms. Also contains account of money owed Hudgins by African Americans as of 1 June 1861; an account of J. D. Marchant with William M. Dixon, coachmaker. Also includes a deed, 11 November 1887 and recorded 4 January 1890, for 11 1/2 acres in Mathews County. Also contains a brochure, 1879, for the Lamington School in Hampton, Virginia, and minutes, 1853-1854, for Chesapeake Lodge No. 89 for the International Order of Odd Fellows. Also one daybook and two ledgers, 1846-1870, for Hudgins General Store in Mathews County.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject.
Contents List
- Papers of the Commissioner of Accounts, 1859, 1869-1893 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Papers of Wm. H. Hudgins as Commissioner of Accounts, 1868-1895 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Papers of Wm. H. Hudgins as Commissioner of Accounts, 1879-1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Papers of Wm. H. Hudgins as Justice of the Peace, 1870-1886 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Papers of Wm. H. Hudgins as Justice of the Peace, 1877-1886 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Papers of Wm. H. Hudgins as Justice of the Peace, 1878-1895 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Papers of Wm. H. Hudgins as Commissioner in Chancery, 1874-1886 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Examination of the County Treasurer's Bond, 1879, 1883, 1891-1892 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Estate Papers, 1861-1894 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Estate Papers, 1867-1892 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Papers of the Respress Estate, 1880-1882 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Papers of the Estate of John J. Callis, 1882-1894 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Fiduciaries, 1871-1892 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Wm. H. Hudgins Promissory Notes, 1853-1862 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Account: Amount Owing by Negroes, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Notice of Lamington School Near Hampton, Virginia, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Account of J. D. Marchant with William M. Dixon, Coachmaker, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Deed, 11 November 1887, for 11 1/2 acres in Mathews County from Robert E. Hudgins and Martha L. Hudgins to William A. Crocket. Deed recorded in Mathews County 4 January 1890. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Blank Legal Forms (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Chesapeake Lodge No. 89, International Order of Odd Fellows, Minutes, 1853-1854 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Hudgins General Store Daybook, 1850-1853 (Box 2)
- Hudgins General Store Ledger, 1846-1848 (Box 2)
- Hudgins General Store Ledger, 1869-1870 (Box 2)